<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kalbasit</title>
    <link>https://kalbas.it/</link>
    <description>Recent content on kalbasit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kalbas.it/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage Hugo themes with Nix</title>
      <link>https://kalbas.it/2019/02/27/manage-hugo-themes-with-nix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalbas.it/2019/02/27/manage-hugo-themes-with-nix/</guid>
      <description>This is the second article in the series of articles about Hugo and Nix. If you have not read the previous article, please do so before reading this article.
Introduction In this article, I&amp;rsquo;m going to explore how to manage Hugo themes with Nix. But before I talk about how Nix can help here, let me lay out the problems I find with Hugo themes.
A Hugo theme requires one or more of the following resources:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage a static website with Hugo and Nix</title>
      <link>https://kalbas.it/2019/02/26/manage-a-static-website-with-hugo-and-nix/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 17:21:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalbas.it/2019/02/26/manage-a-static-website-with-hugo-and-nix/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Over the past couple of years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Hugo on and off for my blog, as well as for some static websites I maintain. On many occasions, I have started to hack on my site, only to realsize that my theme &amp;ndash; as submoduled into the repository &amp;ndash; is no longer compatible with the most recent version of Hugo that I have installed on my system.
This blog post describes how to migrate from an environment controlled by the host operating system to a reproducible environment regardless of the host.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://kalbas.it/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 17:29:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalbas.it/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi there! My name is Wael Nasreddine and I&amp;rsquo;m a software engineering architect working at KeepTruckin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup a website on AWS with CoreOS and Docker</title>
      <link>https://kalbas.it/2016/08/21/setup-a-website-on-aws-with-coreos-and-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 18:21:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalbas.it/2016/08/21/setup-a-website-on-aws-with-coreos-and-docker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been quite some time since I shared my knowledge and the daily
challenges that I overcome. I always wanted to get back into writing as
it has always been therapeutic for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about how this blog is being hosted. We will
start from the top down by looking first at the application level, then
we will take a look at the hosting, the deployment, the server and
finally the cloud provisioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;micro-containerized-cluster&#34;&gt;Micro-Containerized cluster&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most ideal stack today would be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Etcd2 cluster with at least 5 nodes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kubernetes cluster with at least 3 master nodes and 2 minion nodes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s encrypt generated SSL certificates for all websites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Route53 for managing the DNS zones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All managed using Terraform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s exactly what I did for work, but it&amp;rsquo;s way overkill and
financially unacceptable for a blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stack I designed for this blog:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One t2.micro instance running NginX containers with support for SSL
certificates from Let&amp;rsquo;s encrypt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Route53 for managing the DNS zones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All managed using Terraform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>